Finding Aid for the Joseph Byrne Lockey Papers LSC.0127
UCLA Library Special Collections
Joseph Byrne Lockey papers
1763-1946
UCLA Library Special Collections
Lockey, Joseph Byrne
LSC.0127
7.5 linear feet (15 boxes and 5 oversize boxes)
Joseph Byrne Lockey (1877-1946) was a assistant professor of history (1922-25), associate professor (1925-29) and professor (1929-1946) at UCLA specializing in Pan-Americanism. The collection consists of typescripts and photocopies of correspondence, documents and papers relating to the history of Central America, East Florida, and the islands of the Caribbean, especially concerning English and American diplomacy in this area.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Julien C. Yonge, 1948.
Gift of Robert W. Frazer.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9922210273606533
Biography
Joseph Byrne Lockey was born February 2, 1877 in Florida; BS, University of Nashville (1902); MA (1909) and PhD. (1920), Columbia University; departmental inspector of public instruction for Peru, 1909-14; served as lieutenant in U.S. Infantry in France during World War I; assistant professor of history (1922-25), associate professor (1925-29), professor (1929-1946), UCLA; wrote on Pan-Americanism; died 1946.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of typescripts and photocopies of correspondence, documents and papers relating to the history of Central America, East Florida, and the islands of the Caribbean, 1763-1925, especially concerning English and American diplomacy in this area. Also includes material on the teaching of the history of this area and personal correspondence.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Central America (Boxes 1-4).
Florida (Boxes 5-10).
Manuscripts (Boxes 11-14).
Notes and correspondence (Box 15).
Index cards (Box 16).
Microfilm (17-20).
Related Material
Education of a Bibliophile {oral history transcript} / Edwin H. Carpenter, interviewee. UCLA Oral History Department interview, 1977. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Florida -- History.; Caribbean area -- History.; Historians -- United States -- Archives.; Lockey, Joseph Byrne, 1877-1946--Archives.; University of California, Los Angeles--Faculty -- Archives
- Central America
  - 1. Central America (Guatemala, Nicaragua, British Honduras, etc.), 1837-38
    - List of Foreign Office Documents., 1.; 7pp. (7 × 9 ruled paper) pencil. (Box 1)
    - Macdonald, A. to Glenelg. Belize, May 1, 1837.; 2.; 2pp. (Copy, typed, of Foreign Office 252/7). (Box 1)
    - Palmerston to Chatfield, Frederick. London, August 22, 1837.; 3.; 1p. (Copy, typed, of Foreign Office 252/7). (Box 1)
    - Stephen, James to J. Backhouse. London, August 22, 1837.; 4.; 1p. (Copy, typed, of Foreign Office 252/7). (Box 1)
    - Bidwell, John to Frederick Chatfield. London, September 8, 1837.; 5.; 1p. (Copy, typed, of Foreign Office 252/7). (Box 1)
    - Palmerston to Frederick Chatfield. London, December 15, 1837.; 6.; 1p. (Copy, typed, of Foreign Office 252/7). (Box 1)
    - Notes on Foreign Office Documents., 7.; 21pp. (7 × 9" ruled paper) pencil. (Box 1)
    - Cox Swasey and Company (and 11 other signers) to His Majesty Robert Charles Frederic. Cape Gracios a Dios, January 1, 1838.; 8.; 4pp. (Copy, typed, of Foreign Office 15/24). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Fred to Palmerston. Central America, San Salvador, February 23, 1838.; 9.; 4pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/20 no.14 - 7 × 9 paper). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Fred to Palmerston. Central America, San Salvador, February 23, 1838.; 10.; 1p. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/20 - 7 × 9 paper). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Fred to Macdonald. Central America, San Salvador, February 23, 1838.; 11.; 2pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/20 - 7 × 9 paper). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Fred to Palmerston, K.B. Central America, San Salvador, March 1, 1838.; 12.; 5pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/20 no.20 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Stephen, James to J. Backhouse. London, March 15, 1838.; 13.; 2pp. with enclosures (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/21-7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
      - Memorandum: Palmer, March 19, 1838.; 1/.; 2pp. (Box 1)
      - Macdonald, A. to Glenelg. Belize, October 25, 1837.; 2/.; 5pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/21). 7 × 9 paper, ruled. (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Fred to Macdonald. Central America, San Salvador, May 16, 1838.; 14.; 2pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/20 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Palmerston to Chatfield, Frederick. Foreign Office, July 4, 1838.; 15.; 2pp. (Copy, typed, of Foreign Office 252/7). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Fred to Palmerston. Central America, San Salvador, July 25, 1838.; 16.; 4pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/20 no.45 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Stephen, James to W. Fox-Stranways. London, September 13, 1838.; 17.; 2pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/21 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Fred to Palmerston. Central America, San Salvador, September 20, 1838.; 18.; 1p. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/20 - no.53 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Note., 19.; Pencil, 7 × 9 paper. 1p. (Box 1)
    - Palmerston to Colonel Galindo. Foreign Office, October 15, 1838.; 20.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 7/252). (Box 1)
    - Stephen, James to W. Fox-Strangway. London, December 31, 1838.; 21.; 2pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/21 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Macdonald, A. to Glenelg. Belize, October 24, 1838.; 22.; 4pp. (Copy, Pencil, of Foreign Office 15/21 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Garvan, Hugh to (unknown). Coxwain's Hole Key, September 3, 1838.; 23.; 1p. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/21 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Loustalet, Circular Notice, Elina, August 31, 1838.; 24.; 1p. (Copy, pencil - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Macdonald, A. to Hugh Garvan. Belize, September 10, 1838.; 25.; 2pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/21 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Macdonald, A. to The Commandant of Truxillo. Belize, September 10, 1838.; 26.; 2pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/21 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Fred to Col. Office. Belize, September 13, 1838.; 27.; 1p. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/21 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
  - 2. Central America (Guatemala, Nicaragua, British Honduras, etc.), 1839
    - List of Foreign Office Documents, 1.; 7pp. (7 × 9 ruled paper) pencil. (Box 1)
    - Palmerston to Fred Chatfield. Foreign Office, January 24, 1839.; 2.; 1p. (Copy, pencil (7 × 9 ruled paper) of Foreign Office 15/22. (Box 1)
    - Palmerston to Fred Chatfield, March 23, 1839.; 3.; 1p. (Copy, pencil - 7 × 9 ruled paper of Foreign Office 15/22). (Box 1)
    - Palmerston to Frederick Chatfield. Foreign Office, January 24, 1839.; 4.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 252/7). (Box 1)
    - Symonds, Thomas M.C. to (unknown). Port Royal, May 27, 1839.; 5.; 2pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/22 - 7 × 9 ruled paper) [Enclosed in letter from P.J. Douglas, Commodore, to Vice-Adm. Sir Thomas Harvey, Commander-in-chief. May 27, 1839. Foreign Office 15/22]. (Box 1)
    - Alvarez, M. to W. Chatfield. San Salvador, June 10, 1839.; 6.; 5pp. (Copy, pencil - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
      General note
      [Enclosed in W. Chatfield's no.21]
    - Chatfield, Fred to the Central American Government. San Salvador, June 11, 1839.; 7.; 3pp. (Copy, pencil - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Fred to Viscount Palmerston. San Salvador, June 20, 1839.; 8.; 8pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/22, no.21 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Fred to Viscount Palmerston. San Salvador, June 28, 1839.; 9.; 1p. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/22, no.22 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Barrow, Jn. to W. Fox-Strangways. Admiralty, July 1, 1839.; 10.; 1p. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/22 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Palmerston to Frederick Chatfield. Froeign Office, September 21, 1839.; 11.; 2pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/22 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). Also typewritten copy (Foreign Office 252/7). (Box 1)
    - Strangways, W. Fox to (unknown). Foreign Office, September 23, 1839.; 12.; 1p. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/22 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Pennington, G.J. to (unknown). Treasury Chambers, October 21, 1839.; 13.; 1p. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/22 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Backhouse, J. to (unknown). Foreign Office, October 23, 1839.; 14.; 1p. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/22 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Note., 15.; Pencil - 7 × 9 ruled paper. 1p. (Box 1)
    - Escalona to the Magistrate of the Parochial District of Mangles. Republic of New Granada, Province of Cartagena, San Andreas, December 4, 1839.; 16.; 3pp. (Copy, handwritten, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/24 Enclosure 1 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
  - 3. Central America (Guatemala, Nicaragua, British Honduras, etc.), 1840
    - List, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/23., 1.; 2pp. (7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - List, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/24., 2.; 3pp. (7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Extract from a mercantile letter from Guatemala addressed to a house of business in London., 3.; 2pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/24 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Cox, Wm. and others to His Majesty Robert Charles Frederic. Cape Gracios a Dios, January 31, 1840.; 4.; 4pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/24 Enclosure 3 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Frederic, R.C. to Colonel Macdonald. Belize, February 12, 1840.; 5.; 3pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/24 enclosure 2 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Macdonald, A. to (unknown). Belize, February 29, 1840.; 6.; 8pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/24 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Fred to Viscount Palmerston. Central America, Guatemala, March 23, 1840.; 7.; 10pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/23 no.12. - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Macdonald, A. to John Russell. Belize, March 26, 1840.; 8.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/24 - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Fred to Viscount Palmerston. Central America, Quatemala, April 6, 1840.; 9.; 1p. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/23 - 20. 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
      - Macdonald, A. to Fred Chatfield. Government House, March 25, 1840.; 1.; 1p. (Copy, pencil - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
      - Macdonald, A. to General Morazon. Government House, Honduras, March 25, 1840.; 2.; 2pp. (Copy, pencil - 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
      - Chatfield, Fred to A. MacDonald. Central America, Guatemala, April 6, 1840.; 3.; 4pp. (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/23, no.20. 7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - Stephen, James to J. Backhouse. London, May 4, 1840.; 10.; (Copy, pencil, of Foreign Office 15/24 - 7 × 9 ruled paper) 4pp. (Box 1)
    - Barrow, John to Lord Leveson. Admiralty, May 5, 1840.; 11.; (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/24) 1p. (Box 1)
    - Stephen, James to J. Backhouse. London, May 1840.; 12.; 1p. (Copy, trypewritten, of Foreign Office 15/24). (Box 1)
    - Note., 13.; Typewritten. 1p. (Foreign Office 15/24). (Box 1)
    - Russell, J. to Colonel Macdonald. London, June 16, 1840.; 14.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/24). (Box 1)
    - Stephen, James to J. Backhouse. Colonial Office, June 19, 1840.; 15.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/24). (Box 1)
    - Palmerston to Frederick Chatfield. Foreign Office, July 15, 1840.; 16.; 5pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 252/7). (Box 1)
    - Macdonald, A. to William Hell. Belize, September 23, 1840.; 17.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Macdonald, A. to Señor Don Rivera Paz. Belize, September 23, 1840.; 18.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Macdonald, A. to Evan Nepean. Belize, September 25, 1840.; 19.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of F.P. 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Nepean, Evan to Colonel MacDonald. Belize, September 29, 1840.; 20.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Hall, William to Colonel MacDonald. British Consulate, Guatemala, October 17, 1840.; 21.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Hall, William to Colonel MacDonald. British Consulate, Guatemala, October 24, 1840.; 22.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Admiralty Letter of, October 30, 1840.; 23.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of War Office 15/24). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to William Hall. Belize, November 11, 1840.; 24.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to William Hall. Belize, November 11, 1840.; 25.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Note. Foreign Office 15/26, November 11, 1840.; 26.; 1p. Typewritten. (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to Señor Don Rivera Paz. Belize, November 11, 1840.; 27.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Smith, R. Vernon to J. Backhouse. London, November 27, 1840.; 28.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/24). (Box 1)
    - Note. Foreign Office 15/24, November 27, 1840.; 29.; Typewritten. 1p. (Box 1)
    - Russell, J. to Colonel MacDonald. London, November 27, 1840.; 30.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/24). (Box 1)
    - Hall, William to Colonel MacDonald. British Consulate, Guatemala, December 6, 1840.; 31.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Backhouse, J. to [Unknown]. Foreign Office, December 15, 1840.; 32.; 5pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/24). (Box 1)
  - 4. Central America, 1841
    - List of Foreign Office documents., 1.; 14pp. Pencil (7 × 9 ruled paper). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to The Chief of the Government of Costa Rica. Belize, British Honduras, January 5, 1841.; 2.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Bidwell, John to Consul Chatfield. Foreign Office, January 13, 1841.; 3.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Fred to Viscount Palmerston. London, January 13, 1841.; 4.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Bidwell, John to Chatfield. Foreign Office, January 16, 1841.; 5.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to John Russell. Belize, January 23, 1841.; 6.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to The President of Guatemala. Belize, January 30, 1841.; 7.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to The Chief of the Government of the state of Costa Rica. Belize, February 5, 1841.; 8.; (Copy, Stypewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25) 1p. (Box 1)
    - Stephen, James to J. Backhouse. London, February 5, 1841.; 9.; 2pp. total. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). Plus a typewritten duplicate. (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to Lord John Russell. Belize, February 10, 1841.; 10.; (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). 1p. (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to Lord John Russell. Belize, February 11, 1841.; 11.; (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). 1p. (Box 1)
    - Note. Foreign Office 15/26., 12.; 1p. Typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Barrow, John to Lord Leveson. Admiralty, February 22, 1841.; 13.; (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26) 1p. (Box 1)
    - Hall, William to Viscount Palmerston, February 27, 1841.; 14.; Extract, 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. and J.W. Carter to [Unknown]. Belize, February 1, 1841.; 15.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Hall, William to Colonel MacDonald and Capt. Carter. British Consulate, Guatemala, February 27, 1841.; 16.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Palmerston to Colonel MacDonald. Foreign Office, March 10, 1841.; 17.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Palmerston to Vice Consul Hall. Foreign Office, March 10, 1841.; 18.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Stephen, James to J. Backhouse. London, March 17, 1841.; 19.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Stephen, James to J. Backhouse. London, March 24, 1841.; 20.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield to The Right Honorable Earl of Aberdeen. London, April 1, 1841.; 21.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Fred to Viscount Palmerston. London, April 5, 1841.; 22.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Mr. Upton. Foreign Office, May 10, 1841.; 23.; (Foreign Office 15/26) 1p. (Box 1)
    - Stephen, James to J. Backhouse. London, April 5, 1841.; 24.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Foster, John to William Hall. Realejo, April 7, 1841.; 25.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Upton, George to Viscount Palmerston. 68 Old Broad St., May 6, 1841.; 26.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Backhouse, J. to [Unknown], May 13, 1841.; 27.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Upton, George to Viscount Palmerston. 68 Old Broad Street, May 19, 1841.; 28.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Frederic, Robert Charles, King of the Mosquito Nation. Proclamation., 29.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26). (Box 1)
    - Hall, William to Viscount Palmerston. British Consulate, Quatemala, May 22, 1841.; 30.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Notes on correspondence. Foreign Office, August 16, 1841.; 31.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Guevara, M. to The Vice Consul of Her Britannick Majesty, Realejo, Government House, San Jose., March 5, 1841.; 32.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
      - Guevera, M. Copy of an article translated from a London periodical, May 22, 1841.; 11.; (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office]/25) 2pp. (Box 1)
    - Extract from a report on the coast and harbour of Boca del Toro by Commander Barnett, May 28, 1841.; 33.; (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26) 2pp. (Box 1)
    - Bidwill, John to Mr. George Upton. Foreign Office, May 31, 1841.; 34.; (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/26) 1p. (Box 1)
    - Hall, William to Viscount Palmerston. British Consulate, Guatemala, May 31, 1841.; 35.; (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25) 2pp. (Box 1)
    - Hall, William to Principal Secretary of the Supreme Government of the State of Guatemala. British Consulate, Guatemala, June 25, 1841.; 36.; (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25) 2pp. (Box 1)
    - Hall, William to Viscount Palmerston. British Consulate, Guatemala, June 26, 1841.; 37.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Hall, William to Colonel MacDonald and W. Dawson. British Consulate, Guatemala, June 26, 1841.; 38.; 6pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Leveson, J. to [Unknown]. Foreign Office, August 14, 1841.; 39.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/27). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to His Excellency, the chief of the State of Nicaragua. North Side of the River. St. John, August 15, 1841.; 40.; 5pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25) Plus five enclosures. (Box 1)
      - Walker, Pat to Señor Manuel Quixano. North Side of the River, St. John, August 13, 1841.; 1.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten). (Box 1)
      - Walker, Pat to Col, MacDonald. North Side of the River, St. John, August 13, 1841.; 2.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten). (Box 1)
      - Shepherd, Peter to Colonel MacDonald. North Side of the River, St. John, Mosquito Shore, August 14, 1841.; 3.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten). (Box 1)
      - Ferrell, E. and others to Colonel MacDonald. North Side of the River, St. John, Mosquito Shore, August 14, 1841.; 4.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten). (Box 1)
      - MacDonald, A. to The Chief of the State of Nicaragua. Government House, Belize, September 4, 1841.; 5.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten). (Box 1)
    - Translation. Manuel Quijano. Boca del Toro, August 22, 1841.; 41.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to The Chief of the State of Salvador. British Honduras, Government House, Belize, October 7, 1841.; 42.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Leveson, J. to [Unknown]. Foreign Office, August 24, 1841.; 43.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/27). (Box 1)
    - Hall, William to Col, Macdonald. Guatemala, September 4, 1841.; 44.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/31). (Box 1)
    - Walker, Pen to [Unknown]. Government Sec. Office, September 4, 1841.; 45.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 252/8). (Box 1)
    - Veteri, Juge de to Colonel Alexander MacDonald. Government House Guatemala, September 25, 1841.; 46.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/31). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, Alexander to the Chief of the State of Nicaragua, September 25, 1841.; 47.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/30). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to Señor Don Jorge Viteri. British Honduras, Government House, Belize, October 7, 1841.; 48.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 252/8). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to the Chief of the State of Salvador. British Honduras, Government House, Belize, October 7, 1841.; 49.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 252/8). (Box 1)
    - Belize Gazette, Saturday, October 9, 1841.; 50.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/30). (Box 1)
    - Orosco, Simon to the Minister for Foreign Affairs of Her Britannick Majesty. Government House, Leon, October 16, 1841.; 51.; 8pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Hall, William to Viscount Palmerston. British Consulate, Guatemala, October 18, 1841.; 52.; 5pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Extract of Letter from Simon Orosco to The Superintendent of the Establishment of Belize A. Macdonald, dated from Department of Correspondence, Government House, Leon, on being copy of Translation by W.E. Hampshire Public Interpreter., October 28, 1841.; 53.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/30). (Box 1)
    - Bidwell, John to Colonel MacDonald. Foreign Office, October 28, 1841.; 54.; (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25) 1p. (Box 1)
    - Canning to [Unknown]. Foreign Office, October 28, 1841.; 55.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - Orosco, Simon to A. MacDonald. Department of Relations, October 28, 1841.; 56.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/31). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to Sir Chas. Metcalfe Bart, November 6, 1841.; 57.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/30). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to the Chiefs of the States of Honduras, Nicaragua, Costa Rica and El Istmo., 58.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/31). (Box 1)
    - Harrison, Robert Monro to John Gough. American Consulate, Kingston, Jamaica, November 10, 1841.; 59.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/30). (Box 1)
    - Metcalfe, C.T. to Lord Stanler. Jamaica, King's House, November 19, 1841.; 60.; 14pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/30). (Box 1)
    - Chatfield, Frederick to Earl of Aberdeen. 6 Pall Mall East, London, November 20, 1841.; 61.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/25). (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, A. to William Hall. British Honduras, Government House, Belize, November 29, 1841.; 62.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/30). (Box 1)
    - Murphy, William J. to Alexander MacDonald. British Honduras, Belize, December 6, 1841.; 63.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/30). (Box 1)